# Mike Vanbuskirk

Senior Systems Engineer

# Location:

Grand Rapids, MI

#### Contact:

em: mvanbus43@gmail.com

## Education:

WGU: 2009-2012 B.Sc - Networks Design and Management

#### Web:

li: linkedin.com/in/mikevanbuskirk q: quora.com/profile/Mike-Vanbuskirk gh: github.com/codevbus

# Summary

Senior Systems Engineer with a primary focus on Linux, DevOps, and Cloud engineering. Extensive experience in some of the largest CDN, Cloud, and E-Commerce platforms in the world. Designed, shipped, and supported production application stacks. Bachelor's degree holder who is passionate about technology and automation, and loves learning new things.

#### Core Skills

#### Platform:

Windows and Linux/Unix-based operating systems. Modern cloud computing platforms including AWS, GCE, and OpenStack.

#### **Development:**

BASH, Python, JavaScript, JSON, Yaml, HTML/CSS, LaTeX. Multi-team collaboration using Git/VCS.

#### **Networking:**

Tier-1 application DNS and loadbalancing deployments, utilizing Route53, ELB/ALB, Citrix Netscaler, and F5 BigIP.

## DevOps:

Experience in DevOps lifecycle, including CI/CD, operational support, 12-factor methodolgies, and laaC(Infrastructure as Code).

#### Other highlights:

Hashicorp suite, including Terraform, Vagrant, Consul, Nomad. Monitoring tools including: DataDog, NewRelic, Solarwinds, ELK, CloudWatch. Containerization and microservice deployments utilizing Docker, ECS, and AWS Lambda.

# **Experience**

## Senior Systems Engineer - The Walt Disney Company

Seattle, WA | July 2016 - Present

System engineer with a DevOps focus supporting multiple customer facing applications.

## Technical Operations Support Engineer III/IV - Amazon

Seattle, WA | September 2014 - June 2016

Tier-1 event management, application & service support, configuration, monitoring, and automation across one of the largest e-commerce & cloud platforms in the world.

## CDN NOC Technician Linux/Unix - Level(3) Communications

Tulsa, OK | June 2013 - August 2014

Monitor and maintain many thousand node global CDN platform, including highly available storage and streaming applications.